There's nothing more determined than poultry with a plan.
Chicken Run is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Nick Park.
The creators of Wallace & Gromit bring you an exciting and original story about a
group of chickens determined to fly the coop–even if they can’t fly!
It’s hardly poultry in motion when Rocky attempts to teach Ginger and her feathered friends to fly…but, with teamwork,
determination and a little bit o’ cluck, the fearless flock plots one last attempt in a spectacular bid for freedom.
Ginger (voice), played by Julia Sawalha.
Rocky (voice), played by Mel Gibson.
Bunty (voice), played by Imelda Staunton.
Babs (voice), played by Jane Horrocks.
Mac (voice), played by Lynn Ferguson.
Mrs. Tweedy (voice), played by Miranda Richardson.
Chicken Run is a 2000 animated adventure comedy film directed by Peter Lord and Nick Park
and written by Karey Kirkpatrick from an original story by Lord and Park.
Produced by Pathé and Aardman Features in partnership with DreamWorks
Animation, it is Aardman's first feature-length film.
The film stars the voices of Julia Sawalha, Mel Gibson, Tony Haygarth, Miranda Richardson, Phil
Daniels, Lynn Ferguson, Timothy Spall, Imelda Staunton, and Benjamin Whitrow.
Set in the countryside of Yorkshire, the film centres on a group of British anthropomorphic chickens who see an American rooster
named Rocky Rhodes as their only hope to escape the farm when their owners want to turn them into chicken pies.
Chicken Run was released in the United States on 23 June 2000
and in the United Kingdom on 30 June 2000.
It was a critical and commercial success, grossing $228 million and becoming
the highest-grossing stop-motion animated film in history.
At the time, this film was DreamWorks Animation's most successful
release, but this was overtaken by Shrek the following year.
A sequel, titled Chicken Run: Dawn of the Nugget, was
released on Netflix on 15 December 2023.
The film explores themes of farm, northern england, escape, freedom, chicken.
The tone is lighthearted.